{
  "sourceFile": "2018-2019-International-Geography-Bee-Regional-Quiz-Tournament-Round-1.txt",
  "count": 10,
  "items": [
    {
      "qno": 1,
      "question": "In 1905, a band of Igorrote headhunters performed mock tribal ceremonies in this place’s Luna Park. The annual July 4th Nathan’s Hot Dog Eating Contest occurs just off the boardwalk at this location, the site of the New York Aquarium, the Wonder Wheel, and the Cyclone roller coaster. For the point, identify this beach neighborhood of Brooklyn, New York.",
      "answer": "Coney Island"
    },
    {
      "qno": 2,
      "question": "The Galata Tower is a 14th-century Genoese structure overlooking the historic district of this city. A church designed by Isidore of Miletus in this city was transformed into a mosque in the 15th century but lost its ceremonial functions to the Blue Mosque. The Golden Horn, an inlet of the Sea of Marmara, is the historic harbor of this city. This city straddles the Bosporus, which separates Europe from Asia. For the point, name this most populous city in Turkey.",
      "answer": "Istanbul"
    },
    {
      "qno": 3,
      "question": "This country’s central region includes the Yushan Mountains and Sun Moon Lake. Kaohsiung is the largest city and port in the south of this country. A skyscraper in this country was inspired by the shape of bamboo and is named for its 101 stories. This island formerly known as Formosa is led by the Kuomintang. For the point, name this country with capital Taipei.",
      "answer": "Taiwan"
    },
    {
      "qno": 4,
      "question": "Ulan-Ude is the capital of this region’s Buryat Republic. The Tunguska Event was a large explosion east of the Yenisey River in this region, where the Angara River drains Lake Baikal. This region’s city of Novosibirsk is on the Ob River, while its port of Vladivostok is on the Sea of Japan. The Ural Mountains serve as the western border of, for the point, what large region of Russia?",
      "answer": "Siberia"
    },
    {
      "qno": 5,
      "question": "Curitiba is the capital of a Brazilian province that shares its name with this river. The cities of Santa Fe and Rosario are on this river, which receives the Iguazu and Pilcomayo as tributaries. The Yacyreta and Itaipu Dams on this river produce all of Paraguay’s electricity. For the point, name this second-longest South American river, which merges with the Uruguay to form the Rio de la Plata.",
      "answer": "Parana River"
    },
    {
      "qno": 6,
      "question": "This country’s Gotjawal Forest is located south of South Jeolla Province on Jeju Island. The Taebaek Mountains, which lie in the east of this country, are the site of its largest port, Busan. In 1950, UN forces made an amphibious landing at Incheon in this country, whose northern border is formed by the DMZ at the 38th parallel. For the point, name this country with its capital at Seoul.",
      "answer": "South Korea"
    },
    {
      "qno": 7,
      "question": "The island of Surtsey is one of this type of geological feature, “cinder” examples of which are formed by tephra. The destroyed town of Herculaneum lies near one of these features in Italy. A national park named for these features on Hawaii’s Big Island is home to Mauna Loa. 452 of these lie along the “Ring of Fire” around the Pacific Ocean. For the point, name this type of geological feature whose eruptions can spew ash and lava.",
      "answer": "volcanoes"
    },
    {
      "qno": 8,
      "question": "This country owns the Kerguelen Islands, as well as the islands of Wallis and Futuna in the south Pacific. In 2018, the Kanak people voted against New Caledonia’s independence from this country. This country owns a South American territory that contains the primary launch site of the European Space Agency, Devil’s Island, and the city of Cayenne. For the point, name this country whose overseas departments include Guadaloupe and Martinique.",
      "answer": "France"
    },
    {
      "qno": 9,
      "question": "Slaves in this country developed capoeira, a martial art that combines acrobatics, dance, and music. This country’s bossa nova style of music is exemplified by the song “The Girl From Ipanema.” The Alvorada Palace and Planalto Palace were both designed by Oscar Niemeyer for this country’s capital. For the point, name this country where the statue of Christ the Redeemer overlooks Rio de Janeiro.",
      "answer": "Federative Republic of Brazil"
    },
    {
      "qno": 10,
      "question": "L’Orient exploded during a battle in this sea at Aboukir [AH-boo-ker] Bay. Henry the Navigator captured this sea’s port of Ceuta [THAY-oo-tah], which lies near the Barbary Coast. The Knights Hospitaller operated from Rhodes before moving to Malta, another island in this sea. For the point, name this sea from which Richard the Lionhearted occupied Cyprus and Sicily.",
      "answer": "Mediterranean Sea"
    }
  ]
}